字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
《闪电侠》本季回顾
This season on "The Flash"...
我回到过去创造出了另一条时间线
I went back in time and created an alternate timeline,
一个全新的存在
a whole new existence.
我创造了闪点  改变了一切
I created Flashpoint and changed everything.
-你是谁  -萨维塔  极速之神
- Who are you? - Savitar. The God of Speed.
你说我把你困在了未来  在哪
You said that I trapped you in the future. Where?
唯一你能够关住我的地方
The only place that could hold me.
神速力
The Speed Force.
爱瑞丝·韦斯特
Iris West,
-你愿意嫁给我吗  -愿意
- will you marry me? - Yes!
布兰德博士发明了一种技术
Dr. Brand invents the technology
可以把萨维塔困在神速力中
that traps Savitar in the Speed Force.
-祝好运  -我们不想跟你打
- Good luck with that. - We don't wanna fight you.
我们是你的朋友  你的家人
We're your friends. Your family.
凯特琳  我爱你
Caitlin, I love you.
你们任何人我都没爱过
I never loved any an you.
凯特琳现在在和萨维塔合作
Caitlin is working with Savitar.
-凯特琳死了  -我不觉得
- Caitlin is dead. - Not to me.
我知道你是谁了
I know who you are.
我就是未来的闪电侠
I am the future Flash.
等我掌控了所有时间
When I have control of all of time,
被抛弃  被遗忘的人将会是你
it will be you who is abandoned and forgotten!
而我只需要让爱瑞丝死
And I only need for Iris to die
你就会陷入无尽的黑暗中
so that you are driven so far into the dark
我就可以重生了
that I can be born.
我会阻止你
I'm gonna stop you.
没有用
It didn't work.
你输了  巴里
You lose, Barry!
不
No!
爱瑞丝
Iris!
不
Oh, no.
爱瑞丝
Iris?
BA
B.A.?
什么
What?
BA
B.A.
HR
H.R.?
老爸
Dad.
宝贝
Baby?
是我
Yeah.
我不明白
I don't understand.
是HR
It was H.R.
再见
Till the next one.
HR
H.R.
我来救你出去
Let's get you out of here.
其他人呢
Where is everybody else?
我不能说
I couldn't tell...
巴里或萨维塔会知道我来了
Barry, or Savitar,would know I was coming.
我来救你出去
Let's get you out of here.
好
Okay.
抓住她
Get her.
我们跑不过他们
We can't outrun them.
是的  跑不过
No, we can't.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
萨维塔找到你都是因为我
I'm the reason Savitar found you.
我要弥补我的过错
I need to remedy that.
不能这样  给我
Not like this. Give me that.
住手  你要的人是我
Don't! I'm the one he wants.
好吗  求你了  不要伤害他
Okay? Please, don't hurt him.
HR
H.R.!
特蕾西
Tracy.
不
No.
不要  不要
No. No.
没  没事的
It's-- it's okay.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
我不要做胆小鬼
I couldn't be a coward.
我不是胆小鬼
I'm not a coward.
我们刚刚找到彼此
We just found each other.
我知道
I know.
我们的故事一定很精彩
Our story would be brilliant.
你一定会活得精彩
You will be brilliant.
你的人生一定很辉煌  特蕾西·布兰德
You will be glorious, Tracy Brand.
一定会
You will be.
我  我亲眼看到过
I've seen... seen it with my own eyes.
我爱你
I love you.
不  BA
Oh, no. B.A.?
-我在这  -BA
- I'm right here. - B.A.
转告西斯科
Will you tell Cisco...
告诉他
Please tell him...
你能转告他吗
Will you tell him that?
帮我个忙
For me?
-好  -好
- Yeah. - Good.
那
Now...
去阻止萨维塔吧
go stop Savitar.
HR  HR
H.R. H.R.
萨维塔拿走了神速力火箭筒
Savitar took the Speed Force bazooka.
再见了  震波
Bye-bye, Vibe.
别杀他
Keep him alive.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
因为我需要他帮我们造个东西
Because I need him to build something for us.
闪电侠在危机中消失
由爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦撰写
爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦
"Iris West-Allen."
署名变回来了
It changed back.
这是不是和我想的一样
Does that mean what I think it means?
是的  乔  未来又变回来了
Yeah, Joe. The future's ours again.
由爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦撰写
2024年4月25日星期四
萨维塔
Savitar?
-事情不对劲  -怎么了
- Something's wrong. - What is it?
她没死
She's... not dead.
怎么可能
How is that possible?
HR
H.R.
他代替了她
He took her place.
HR
H.R.
你不是说HR活着吗
I thought you said H.R. lives.
他现在死了
Not anymore!
如果爱瑞丝没死
If Iris doesn't die...
就意味着未来改变了
That means the future's changing.
你的未来也变了
So is yours.
闪电侠
第三季
第二十三集
[本季终]
什么
What?
HR死了  不敢相信
H.R.'s dead? I... I can't believe that.
-特蕾西还好吧  -不好
- Is Tracy all right? - Not good.
她只想一个人待会
She just wants to be alone.
没时间哀伤
There'll be time to mourn.
现在我们要想想下一步该怎么做
Right now, we need to figure out our next move.
说了上百万次
So for the millionth time,
我完全搞不懂这些穿越的事
I'm lost on all this time travel stuff.
现在萨维塔会怎么样
What happens now? With Savitar?
爱瑞丝没死  那事情就变了吧
Iris didn't die. So that changes things, right?
既然爱瑞丝没死
I mean, since Iris didn't die,
未来的我不会走上同样的黑暗道路
future me never goes down that same dark path.
我就从未创造出时间残余去对抗萨维塔
I never create time remnants to fight Savitar.
如果未来的你从未创造出这些时间残余
And if future you never creates these time remnants,
那萨维塔本身就从未出现过
then Savitar himself is never born.
没错  只要时间悖论赶上了他  那...
Precisely. Once the time paradox catches up with him, then...
他的存在就会被抹去
he'll be erased from existence.
但我看到他了  没有消失
But I saw him. He didn't disappear.
-还没  -但是会的  乔
- Not yet. - But he will, Joe.
知道他要多久才消失吗
Any guesses how long that's gonna take?
也许几个小时吧
Maybe a few hours?
他在几小时内也会带来很多损害
He can do a lot of damage in a few hours.
我们不能就这样干坐着
Well, guys, we can't just sit around
等着萨维塔消失
and wait for Savitar to disappear.
可如果萨维塔被抹去  他就不会变成萨维塔
But Savitar won't become Savitar if he's erased.
除非在悖论袭击他之前
Not unless he pulls off whatever he's got in mind
他完成了他想到的大计
before the paradox hits him.
他偷走火箭筒是有原因的
He stole the bazooka for a reason.
是啊  为什么
Yeah, why?
我不知道  但是记住
I don't know, but remember,
他已经计划几个世纪了
he's been planning this for centuries.
他想成为神
He wants to be a god.
他肯定需要火箭筒和凯特琳
He must need the bazooka, and Caitlin,
来达成他的目标
to achieve his goals.
大家有什么好消息吗
Anybody got any good news?
其实有
Actually, uh, voilà.
-那是什么  -警探
- What is that? - This, Detective,
这个能治愈凯特琳
is the cure for Caitlin.
你说笑吧  你想到办法了吗
You're kidding. You figured it out?
不是我一个人  有人帮了我
Not by myself. With the help of...
凯特琳的母亲
Caitlin's mother.
这是实验性基因治疗
This is experimental gene therapy.
这会改写凯特琳的超能力DNA
This? This will rewrite Caitlin's meta-DNA.
就能让凯特琳变回
This will bring back...
原来的样子
Caitlin.
我搜过树林了
I searched the forest.
萨维塔和凯特琳都不见了
Savitar and Caitlin were gone.
西斯科也是
So was Cisco.
萨维塔手上有他俩
Savitar has 'em both.
你最好有备用计划
Oh, you better have a plan B,
因为我觉得你的原计划不是很有效
'cause I don't think your plan A worked out too well.
修好它
Fix this.
修好什么
Fix what?
神速力火箭筒吗
The Speed Force bazooka?
不是我命名的
Hey, I didn't name it.
不是我命名的  说明不是我造的
If I didn't name it, I didn't make it.
不是我造的
And if I didn't make it,
说明我不知道它的原理
I don't know how it works.
你知道的足以改造它了
Oh, you know enough about it to alter what it does.
我懂了  你想让我改造它
Oh, I see. You want me to alter it.
好吧  你想让我把它改造成什么
Well, what do you want me to alter it into?
吹风机  华夫机
Like, a hair dryer? Or a waffle maker?
我知道了  或许做成能修复
Oh, I know. Maybe something that's gonna
你称之为脸的那张薄皮披萨
fix that thin-crust pizza you call a face.
一台维度内量子连接器
An intradimensional quantum splicer.
一台连接器
A splicer.
我确实有备用计划
I do have a plan B.
我打开时间传送门  站在神速力前
I open a time portal, exposing the Speed Force,
你向我发射  我就成为贯穿
you shoot me with that, and I become fragmented
所有时间的片段
throughout all of time.
过去  现在  将来
The past, present, future.
在那之后  悖论就没法找到我
After that, the paradox can't reach me.
你想将自己连接到所有时间
You wanna splice yourself throughout time?
存在于每分每秒之中
Exist in every single moment there ever was?
所有人都知道  并通过某个意识联系起来
All of us aware and connected through one consciousness.
我会无处不在  每时每刻
I'll be everywhere-- every hour, every minute.
到时候
And then,
我会统治从大爆炸到世界末日的每时每刻
I will rule from the Big Bang until the end of the world.
你想让我造出这东西
You wanted us to build this thing.
你觉得我为什么会让你们这些傻瓜活着
Well, why do you think I let you idiots live?
特蕾西·布兰德在未来把我困在了神速力中
Tracy Brand trapped me in the Speed Force in the future.
我只需要让她提早一点点造出它
All I had to do was get her to build this a little earlier
让我的好哥们进行改造
and have my best friend make all the adjustments.
我不是你的哥们
I'm not your friend.
赶紧
Get...
开工  弗朗西斯科
to work, Francisco.
不如我什么也不做
How about I sit on my ass
让你的存在永远被抹去
and let you obliterate permanently from existence?
怎么样
How's that sound?
那就是你的计划
That's your plan?
不成功就用逆闪那招
Do it or you'll Reverse-Flash me?
不是对你
Not you.
是对她
Her.
你知道我想起了什么吗
You know what I'm remembering?
朱利安刚回到尖端科研实验室
Julian just got back to S.T.A.R Labs.
他有解药
He has the cure.
他可以复原她
He can turn her back.
你可以找回她  就快成功了
You can have her back. You're so close.
但她死了就不行
But not if she's dead.
让那个技术天才好好干活吧
So put that mechanical genius to good work.
造出我需要的东西
Make me what I need.
然后我就会放你俩走
And I will let you both go.
我恨斯旺
I hated Thawne...
还有极速
And Zoom.
他们夺走了我太多
They took so much from me.
我也恨萨维塔
And I've hated Savitar
威胁要夺走你
for threatening to take you away from me too.
但他失败了
But he didn't.
是的
I know.
愤怒会产生力量
There is strength in anger.
我以前利用过那股力量
I've used it before.
我们坐在这儿  带着愤怒
And so we sit here, with our anger,
想找出一个办法伤害或者杀死萨维塔
trying to think of a way to hurt Savitar or maybe kill him.
我只是觉得这一次  恨不会让我们成功
And I just don't think that hate's gonna get it done this time.
什么意思
What do you mean?
史纳特跟我说的
Something that Snart said to me...
闪电侠应该一直是一名英雄
that the Flash should stay a hero, all the way,
有时候这不代表你是挥拳最有力
and sometimes that it's not about who can punch the hardest
跑得最快的人
or run the fastest.
那你准备怎么办
So what are you gonna do?
出其不意
The last thing he'd expect.
我不确定你会来
I wasn't sure you'd come.
这感觉一定很奇怪
Must be an odd sensation,
获得新的记忆
getting new memories.
你有一个不确定的未来
You having an uncertain future.
你想怎样  我在忙
What do you want? I'm busy.
忙什么
Doing what?
忙着被抹除自己的存在吗
Getting erased from existence?
谁被抹除还不一定呢
We will see which one of us gets erased.
你还打算变成神吗
Are you still planning on becoming a god?
西斯科和凯特琳还活着
Cisco and Caitlin are still alive.
如果你是担心这个
If that's what you're worried about.
我知道  你需要他们  对吧
Oh, I know. You need them, right?
为了完成你宏伟的飞升计划
To pull off your grand ascension.
巴里
Look, Barry,
如果我想跟自己说话
if I wanted to talk to myself,
我在我的地盘就已经说了
I could have done that, back at my lair.
你想干什么
What... do you want?
我想帮你
I wanna help you.
-是吗  -你可没多少时间了
- Really? - You don't have much time--
时间悖论就快找上你了
before the paradox reaches you.
回尖端实验室吧
Come back to S.T.A.R Labs.
放西斯科和凯特琳走
Let Cisco and Caitlin go,
我们想个办法救你
and let us figure out a way to save you.
你真以为我会相信你吗
You really think I'd trust you?
你露面了
You showed up.
所以你记得我来
So you remember me coming here.
我藏了什么把戏吗
Did I have any tricks up my sleeve?
我有计划偷袭你吗
Was I--was I planning on blindsiding you?
我不知道  巴里
I don't know, Barry.
或许看你卑躬屈膝我很开心呢
Maybe I get off on watching you grovel.
不  我觉得不是  我觉得你在听我说
No, I don't think that's it. I think you're hearing me.
我还存在于你的内心
I'm still in there.
内心深处  在那伤疤和痛楚之下
Deep down, buried beneath the scars and the pain,
那里的你  一定感到很孤寂
that part of you that... it must feel so lonely.
但你也知道拥有家庭
But it also knows what it's like to have a family,
拥有朋友的感觉
to have friends.
你可以找回那些东西
You can have all that back.
我们可以不再互相伤害
We can stop hurting each other.
我记得我六岁的时候
I remember when I was six, and, uh...
我求爸爸妈妈
I begged Mom and Dad
让我去米德韦城的科技博览会
to let me go to the Science Expo in Midway.
我们在土路上爆胎了  没有备胎
And, uh, well, we got a flat tire on that dirt road, no spare,
所以我们被拖到了一个单街小镇
so we were towed to that garage in a tiny, one-street town.
当然  我们被困在那里一整天
Of course, we were stuck there all day.
于是我们在那家小餐馆
Then we got ice cream
吃了冰淇淋
and French fries with gravy
还有肉酱薯条
at that little diner.
那一晚  我们看了当地的烟花表演
And then that night, we watched the local fireworks show, and...
那天其实还挺开心的
Actually, it turned out to be a great day.
那是我最喜欢的有关爸爸妈妈的回忆
And it's my favorite memory of Mom and Dad.
那个小镇叫什么来着
What was the name of that town?
梅森维尔
Masonville.
我还存在于你的内心
I'm still in there.
回家吧
Come home.
你如果敢对爱瑞丝做什么
You make a move toward Iris...
他不会的  从今往后
He won't. Killing Iris...
杀爱瑞丝再也不能拯救他了
won't save him now, not anymore.
西斯科呢  凯特琳呢
Where is Cisco? Where's Caitlin?
-他们很安全  -我在问他
- They're safe. - I was asking him.
证明你们能帮我
Show me that you can help me.
然后我就说你们的朋友在哪
Then I will tell you where your friends are.
你现在就告诉我们  否则你就消失
You tell us now, or you go up in smoke.
-这真是疯了  -我不敢相信
- This is bloody insanity. - Can't believe this.
他在这里干什么  他是个禽兽
What is he doing here? He's a monster.
别说了  没事的
Stop! Guys. It's okay.
大家都
Everyone, just...
爱瑞丝  别离他这么近
Iris, stay away from him.
看着我
Look at me.
没事的  看着我
It's okay. Look at me.
我们会帮你的  好吗
We're gonna help you, okay?
谢谢你
Thank you.
好吧  既然我们这位贵客
Right. Well, since our guest here
绑架了我们的两个常驻科学家
has both of our resident scientists hostage,
我们能帮你解决什么时间问题呢
what temporal problem can we help you with?
特蕾西造了神速力陷阱
Tracy built the Speed Force trap.
或许她有办法
Maybe she has an idea.
特蕾西是最可靠的了
Tracy's our best bet.
是吗
Am I?
所以你就是萨维塔
So...you're Savitar.
我听说你将要经历非常糟糕的一天
I hear you're about to have a really bad day.
很好
Good.
特蕾西
Tracy...
他窃取了我的未来
He stole my future.
他凭什么配有未来
Why does he deserve one?
我不该来这的
I shouldn't have come here.
不  我们会让她帮忙的
No. We'll get her to help us.
我想我知道谁或许能说通她
I think I know someone who might be able to get through to her.
我不是HR
I'm not H.R.
我叫哈里森·威尔斯
My name is Harrison Wells.
我来自不同的地球
I'm from a different Earth.
多元宇宙里的  该怎么解释
In the multiverse-- how to explain this?
你是他的二重身
You're... his doppelganger?
对
Yeah.
差不多吧  听着
Something like that--look.
这些人
These people...
他们都是好人
They're good people.
他们需要你帮忙
And they need your help.
帮助那个我花了好几周努力阻止的坏人吗
By helping the bad guy that I spent weeks trying to stop?
不  我不会帮忙
No. I won't do it.
我同意只是因为HR
The only reason I agreed was because of H.R.
HR需要你帮忙
H.R. needs your help.
HR死了
H.R. is dead.
所以你才得留下
That's why you need to stay.
因为萨维塔从你这夺走的
Because of what Savitar took from you,
因为萨维塔从HR夺走的和其他一切事物
because of what Savitar took from H.R.--everything.
HR为他做的事付出了代价
H.R. paid the price that he did
因为他爱这群人
because he loved these people.
因为他爱你
Because he loved you.
那一刻到来时  HR没有逃避
And when the moment came, H.R. didn't run.
回到这感觉很奇怪
Strange being back here.
你记得尖端科研实验室
You remember S.T.A.R Labs?
我什么都记得
I remember everything.
我们就是在这造出了大脑抑制器
This is where we came up with the cerebral inhibitor
来对抗迪沃
to use against DeVoe.
谁
Who?
你们还没遇到
You haven't gotten there yet.
所以现在该怎么办  我住在哪
So how's this gonna work? Where will I live?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我和沃利要做舍友吗
Are Wally and I gonna be bunkmates?
我要再次加入闪电侠队  打击无赖帮吗
Am I supposed to just rejoin Team Flash, fight some Rogues?
你觉得我该过怎样的生活
What kind of life were you thinking I'd lead?
我还没想那么远
I hadn't gotten that far yet.
婚礼时该怎么解释我的存在
How do we explain me at the wedding?
我该坐在新娘这边还是新郎这边
And do I sit bride-side or groom-side?
这些我们都还没有答案
Ah, look, I mean, we don't have all the answers.
我们会想到办法的
You know, we're gonna figure it out.
一起想
Together.
不
No.
不能一起
Not together.
爱恨就在一念间
Love and hate, they're so close.
很容易就会搞混
It's easy to mistake one for the other.
你要跟他共度余生
You're gonna spend the rest of your life with him.
但我记得把戒指给你了
But I remember giving you the ring.
给你唱歌
Singing to you.
向你求婚
Asking you to marry me.
我做不到
I can't do this.
不  你做得到  好吗
No, yes, you can. Okay?
我会陪着你
I will be here for you.
我曾经想杀了你
I tried to kill you.
我杀了HR
I killed H.R.
今后你只能一直背负着这些
And you are going to have to live with that.
但我们不会放弃你
But we won't give up on you, okay?
我们不会这么做
That is not what we do.
大家都会有办法熬过这一切
There is a way through this for all of us.
西斯科和凯特琳在哪
Where are Cisco and Caitlin?
我会带他们回家
I'll bring them home.
怎么了
What is it?
缺口房间正在放射能量
There's energy radiating from the breach room.
系统警报 级别
不是能量泄露
And it's not breach energy.
是魔法石
It's the philosopher's stone.
它在释放所有的能量
It's releasing all its energy.
萨维塔
Savitar.
看起来像要爆炸了
It looks like it's gonna blow.
沃利  带大家出去
Wally. Get everybody out.
完工了吗
Is it finished?
是  完工了
Yeah. It's finished.
真不错
Fantastic.
总有一天萨维塔会背叛你
You know Savitar's gonna turn on you one day.
不  他不会
No, he won't.
萨维塔这样的恶人总会背叛搭档
A bad guy like Savitar always turns on his partners.
这次是例外
Not this time.
醒醒吧
WakeWap!
你这么说  只是因为他对你有所求
You're only saying that because he needs something from you.
一旦他得到他想要的
Once he's done with that,
你也就没用了
it's over for you.
-进展如何  -如我所料
- How'd it go? - As I expected.
傻子才不会这么想
I was a fool to think otherwise.
他去哪了  你做了什么
Where did he go? What did you do?
我解决了一个问题
I got rid of a problem.
几个问题
A few of 'em.
现在我来解决我自己的
Now I can fix mine.
-准备好了吗  -准备好了
- Are we ready? - Yes.
动手吧
Do it.
凯特琳  听我说
Caitlin...listen to me.
他会杀了你
He'll do it.
他会这么做的
He'll kill you.
我愿意碰碰运气
I'll take my chances.
吉普赛
Gypsy!
不  等一下
No, wait. No!
他们逃走你不在意吗
You don't care that they got away?
不  那不重要
No, it doesn't matter.
时间到了
It's time.
我有把握  我正要说服她了
I had that. I was getting through to her.
你差点没命了
You were almost killed.
对外行人来说或许如此
Maybe that's how it looks to the untrained eye.
我可是受过良好训练
These eyes are highly trained.
我知道你身处危险
And I know you were in danger
是我透过多元宇宙震波到了
because I vibed it across the multiverse.
没想到你就这样感谢我的救命之恩
I can't believe this is the thanks I get for saving you!
这不是感谢你
This isn't thanks!
是感谢的对立面
This is the opposite of thanks!
等等
Wait a minute.
你是怎么震波到我有危险的
How did you vibe that I was in trouble?
因为我们心灵相通
Because we are connected.
笨蛋
Jackass.
两位
Guys?
天呐
Oh, my God.
我以为你们出什么事了
I thought something happened to you guys.
双面人说你们死了
Two-Face told me you guys were dead.
我们没事  吉普赛
We're okay. Gypsy...
-吉普赛  -各位好
- Gypsy. - Guys.
吉普赛
Gypsy.
-哈里  -来这帮忙的
- Harry. - Here to help.
那就好
Good.
我知道他想做什么
I know what he's up to.
我们得加快速度
We have to hurry.
我必须在悖论找到我前获得永生
I must become immortal before the paradox reaches me.
今天  我会成为神
Today, I become a god.
所以我才把你带来这
This is why I brought you here.
神速力不喜欢极速者扰乱时间
The Speed Force doesn't like it when speedsters mess with time.
准备好
Get ready.
再见  猎人
See ya later, Hunter.
黑闪电无法战胜的就是  寒冷
The one thing Black Flash can't fight--cold.
终于  成为神的时刻
Finally! To be a god!
什么
What?
不
No!
这个情景我已经等了很久
I've been waiting a long time to do that.
加里克  你是怎么...
Garrick! How did you--
不是他
He didn't.
是我
I did.
我改变了爬弧的极性
By changing the polarity of the climbing arc,
于是把神速力连接器
I changed your Speed Force splicer
变成了神速力万能钥匙
into a Speed Force skeleton key.
你不会以为我真的会把你
Didn't think I was actually gonna let you
变成神吧
become a God, now, did you?
做个了结吧
Let's end this.
走
Go!
动手吧  西斯科  变坏吧
Go ahead, Cisco. Go bad.
不  我绝不会这样
No. I never will.
但我要给你一个选择
But I will give you a choice.
你想再做回凯特琳吗
You wanna be Caitlin again?
你的机会来了
Here's your chance.
当心
Look out!
你会为此付出代价的
You'll pay for what you did!
你可以以这种方式死两次
And you can die the same way twice.
我知道你没那个胆量  凯特琳
I knew you didn't have it in you, Caitlin.
我只剩几分钟了
I only have a few minutes left.
我感觉得到
I can feel it.
但在我走之前
But before I go,
我会杀了乔
I'm gonna kill Joe.
还有沃利
And Wally.
还有爱瑞丝
And Iris.
如果我要死
If I am going to die,
那你所爱的一切也都要去死
then everything you love is going to die too.
不
No!
离飞升只一步之遥却落得如此下场
How's it feel to get so close to your ascension,
这感觉如何
and end up on the ground?
现在我明白了
Now I see.
这都是注定的
It's written.
没有什么是注定的
Nothing's written!
动手吧
Do it!
你杀了我  你就变成了我
You kill me, you become me.
不管怎样  我都能存活
Either way, I live.
我绝不会让痛苦和黑暗决定我是谁
I'll never let the pain, the darkness, determine who I am.
我永远也不会成为你
I will never be you.
这几个月来  你都在努力从他手上救出我
All these months, you were trying to save me from him.
看到了吗  我救了你
Look at that. I saved you.
HR·威尔斯
生命中最重要的两天
一是出生那天
一是找到生命意义的那天
马克·吐温
当我想起HR
When I think of H.R.,
我就想起了
I'm reminded of...
约翰·列侬讲过的一则故事
a story that John Lennon once told.
列侬五岁时  他的老师要他
When Lennon was five years old, his teacher asked him to
写下他长大后想做什么
write down what he wanted to be when he grew up.
列侬写道  "快乐"
Lennon wrote, "Happy."
他的老师说他没有明白老师的问题
His teacher said that he didn't understand the assignment,and
列侬说他们都不懂生活
Lennon said that they didn't understand life.
HR懂生活
H.R. understood life.
他不是一个天才  也没有超级速度
He wasn't a genius, and he didn't have super speed.
但当我们最需要他的时候
But when we needed him the most,
他就成了我们的英雄
he was our hero.
他是我的英雄
He was my hero.
也是我的
Mine too.
好样的  朋友
Good on you, mate.
感谢你这么相信我  HR
Thanks for believing in me, H.R.
我一直想找合适的机会告诉你
Hey, I've been looking for the right time to tell you.
告诉我什么
Tell me what?
HR临死时
Right before H.R. died,
他要我给你捎个话
he asked me to give you a message.
告诉  告诉西斯科
Tell--tell Cisco...
这样做需要勇气  是他给了我勇气
This took strength, and he gave it to me.
我知道你和每个我们认识的
I know that you've had a connection
威尔斯都有感应  但是...
with every Wells that we've met, but...
我也说不上  这个威尔斯很特别
I don't know. Something about this Wells...
是啊...
Yeah...
很特别
something.
失陪一下
I'll be right back.
瞧瞧
Well, well, well.
至少你没穿那些坏女人衣服了
At least you're not shopping at Villains "R" us anymore.
HR的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about H.R.
我肯定你来了他会高兴的
I'm sure he would have appreciated you coming.
你为什么来
Why did you come?
不知道
I don't know.
也许你想回家
Maybe you wanted to come home.
我没有家
I don't have a home.
你有  凯特琳
Yes, you do, Caitlin.
你有  和你的朋友
You do. With your friends.
和我
With me.
抱歉  朱利安
I'm sorry, Julian.
我已经不再是凯特琳了
I'm not Caitlin anymore.
你也不是冰霜杀手
You're not Killer Frost.
不是
No, I'm not.
是别的
I'm something else.
我需要想清楚是什么
And I need to figure out what that is.
自己想清楚
On my own.
西斯科
Cisco.
让我走
Let me go.
-别笑了  -不好笑
- Stop it. - It's not funny.
-我知道  -为什么我们笑
- I know. - Why are we laughing?
我们不应该笑  特别是今天
We should not be laughing. Today, of all days.
我觉得HR会同意的
I think H.R. would have approved.
也许吧
Probably.
你还好吗  我是说
Are you okay? I mean...
你刚做的
with what you did.
我相信某天会影响到我
I'm sure one day, it'll hit me.
将来某天
In the future,
我又有了未来
which... I have again.
是我们
We have.
将来的每一天
Every day of it.
♪每时每刻♪
♪ Every hour, every minute ♪
我想我们选好了
I think we have the song picked out
婚宴跳舞的歌
for the dance at our reception.
这提醒了我
Oh, yeah, that reminds me.
我可以正式
I can officially
-寄出这些了  -这是什么
- mail these. - What are these?
我们婚礼的预定日期卡片
Save the date cards for our wedding.
在我比较有勇气的一天填完的
On one of my braver days, I filled them out.
我从没寄出  不知道我是否能
I never mailed them, not knowing if I would
活着看到婚礼  但是...
live to see the ceremony, but...
但现在我想可以...
but now I guess it's safe to--
送到了
Delivered.
我浪费了好多钱买邮票
I wasted a lot of money on stamps,
非常感谢
thank you very much.
你准备好
Are you...
成为爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦了吗
ready to be Iris West-Allen?
我一直都是爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦
I've always been Iris West-Allen.
一直都是你的
I've always been yours.
怎么回事
What was that?
中城从没有过地震
There's never been an earthquake in Central City.
那不是地震
That wasn't an earthquake.
有什么发现吗
You found something?
所有东西都被烧坏了
Everything's barbecued.
我试着建一个上传路线到卫星
I'm gonna try to establish an uplink to the satellite.
看来不妙
That's not good.
沃利  你可以逆转中子流
Hey, Wally, can you reverse the polarity
-上的极性吗  -马上
- on the neutron flow? - On it.
中城大学刚刚发布了
Central City University just reported an earthquake
里氏6.6级的地震
of 6.6 on the Richter scale.
-这不是地震  -那是什么
- That's not an earthquake. - Then what was it?
地震来自下方  这...
Earthquakes come from down below.This--
这是别的东西
this is something else.
外面越来越严重了
It's gettin' bad out there.
紧急救援马上就会招架不住
Emergency services will soon be overwhelmed.
大家  刚才那一下7.2级了
Guys. 7.2, that last one.
-西斯科  -收到  大家
- Cisco. - Yeah? We're on! Guys.
那是什么
What is that thing?
绝对不是一个缺口
That's definitely not a breach.
我的钚啊
Holy plutonium.
是什么能释放上千焦耳能量
What even emits that many kilojoules?
神速力
The Speed Force.
但是萨维塔死了
But Savitar's dead.
问题就在这里
That's the problem.
这是神速力监狱
It's the Speed Force prison.
它需要一个囚犯
It needs an occupant.
你释放我的时候  它就空了
When you freed me, we emptied it.
-没有囚犯  -它会不稳定
- Without a prisoner... - It goes unstable.
现在它在我们的地球上乱喷能量
And now it's bleeding energy onto our Earth.
好的  我们要怎么阻止它
Okay, so how do we stop this?
给它它想要的东西
By giving it what it needs.
给什么
Which is what?
神速力不稳定
The Speed Force is unbalanced.
我必须让它稳定下来
I have to stabilize it.
-什么  要怎么做  -跑进去
- What? How? - By running into it.
不  不行  巴里
No, you can't. Barry,
你会被永远困在里面的
You'll be trapped in there forever.
如果我不去
If I don't go,
整座城市  甚至整个星球
the whole city, maybe even the entire planet,
-都会被摧毁  -西斯科
- could be destroyed. - Cisco.
还有别的办法  不是吗
There's gotta be another way, right?
巴里  中城需要闪电侠
Barry, Central City needs The Flash.
他们会有的
And they'll have one.
They'll have one.
对吗
Right?
-对吗  -对
- Right?  - Yeah.
兄弟
Mate...
你能留在这里吗
Do you mind sticking around?
为你做任何事都行
Anything for you.
巴里  沃利和杰伊说那就像地狱
Barry. Wally and Jay said they were in hell.
巴里  是你的母亲
Barry, it's your mother.
那是神速力
That's the Speed Force.
巴里不会进地狱的
Barry isn't going to hell.
但就像所有奔跑的人一样
But like all runners must eventually,
他也到达了他的终点
he's reached his finish line.
他的赛程结束了
His race is over.
你不能把他带走
You can't take him with you.
她不会把我带去什么地方的
She's not taking me anywhere.
我得走了
I have to go.
为什么  为什么你要受惩罚
Why? Why are you being punished?
所有的一切
This, all of this,
都是因为我的过错而起
it started with my mistake,
因为闪点
with Flashpoint.
这是  这是我的赎罪
This is-- this is my penance.
是我的救赎
This is my redemption.
我的帅小伙
My beautiful boy.
是时候休息了
It's time to rest.
-别跟她胡来  -我会尽力
- Don't mess it up with her. - I'll do my best.
他们现在都靠你了
They're all gonna look to you now.
我不是个像你一样的英雄
I'm not a hero like you.
你一直是我心里的英雄
You've always been my hero.
我们一直都在努力救爱瑞丝的命
All this time we were trying to save Iris,
而你现在是要说
you're telling me that
我们应该试着救你
we should've been trying to save you too?
你的确救了我  乔
You did save me, Joe.
你救了一个十一岁的
You took an 11-year-old boy
心碎男孩
with a broken heart,
给了他一个家  和那么多爱
and you gave him a home and so much love.
没有哪个父亲比你更爱我这个儿子
No son ever felt more love from a father.
没有哪个儿子比你更让父亲骄傲
No father ever felt more proud of a son.
巴里
Barry.
是时候了
It's time.
巴里
Barry.
这不公平
This isn't fair.
-我知道  -我们应该有个美好的结局
- I know. - We were supposed to have our happy ending.
我准备好做爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦了
I'm ready to be Iris West-Allen.
你永远都会是的
And you always will be.
但你还需要继续生活
But you need to keep living your life.
继续成长
Keep growing.
继续爱
Keep loving.
继续奔跑  为了我
Keep running. For me.
答应我你会继续跑下去  爱瑞丝
Promise me you'll run, Iris.
我答应你
I promise.
我该走了
I got to go.